ALEXANDRA VALLE

North Miami Beach, FL | 646.386.6511 | alexandra.valle.work@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO | GITHUB | LINKEDIN

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks/Tools: React.js, Redux, Flask, Node.js, Express, SQL, Sequelize, SQAlchemy, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Git, REST, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Google API, AWS S3, Shopify, Agile Project Management, Debugging, Deployment

FULL-STACK PROJECTS

WanderPin, Python | Flask | React | Redux | CSS3 Spinoff clone of Pinterest web app. Allows users to image share and social media services. Live | GitHub Repo

- ▶ Deployed AWS S3 and successfully integrated user image uploads. This approach alleviated server load and paved the way for expanding image services.
- Utilized Redux, a state management library, to orchestrate complex data flows within the web app, ensuring efficient state synchronization across React components and enabling a seamless user interface for real-time updates and interactions.
- Devised interactive data visualizations through JavaScript, incorporating algorithms that respond to user input.
- ▷ Leveraged npm packages and dependencies to expand the functionality and features of the project, harnessing the power of the open-source community to efficiently integrate solutions and tools that enriched the user experience and optimized development efforts.

GlobalGrub, Python | Flask | React | Redux | CSS3 Spinoff clone of UberEats web app. Allows users to view, review, and place orders. Live | GitHub Repo

- Collaborated with a team of four engineers, overseeing effective time allocation, equitable distribution of tasks, delegation, and offering feedback on functionality within the framework of Agile Software Development. Additionally, implemented and maintained a streamlined Git workflow to ensure seamless code integration, version control, and efficient collaboration among team members.
- ▷ Streamlined back-end code by implementing adaptable one-to-many flexible relationships that can handle various types of data, by using reusable code modules within the application's models and controllers through the Flask framework.
- ▶ Implemented custom search using redux by creating a centralized state management system to handle search-related data and actions across your application. This approach ensures the search query and results are accessible and consistent throughout the app.

HAHBooking, Express | React | Redux | CSS3

Live | GitHub Repo

Spinoff clone of AirBnb web app. Allows users to post, view, and review locations

- ▶ Implemented Sequelize, an Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) library, to simplify database interactions, allowing for the creation of database models using JavaScript and facilitating efficient database query generation for web applications.
- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs following REST architectural principles, utilizing HTTP methods, and status codes to create a scalable and robust data communication layer for web

applications. This included designing resourceful URIs, implementing CRUD operations, and optimizing data representations, resulting in improved application performance and a seamless user experience.

▶ Engineered user authentication and authorization systems within the web application, employing JWT (JSON Web Tokens) for secure user registration an

EXPERIENCE

Alo Yoga

December 2021 - December 2022

General Manager | New York, NY

- ▶ Responsible for running the Williamsburg location with high volume customer service, profit and loss management as well as setting, monitoring, and driving sales goals.
- ▶ Increased sales volume month to month by 30% and surpassed monthly goals by 20+%.
- ▶ Restructured operations to efficiently track and analyze sales and customer trends to maximize revenue while minimizing expenses.

O.N.S Clothing

October 2019 - December 2021

Retail Department Manager | New York, NY

- ▶ Managed the e-commerce platform Shopify, integrated third-party platforms, and new computer software programs.
- ▶ Incorporated a cloud-based professional employer organization (TriNet) into O.N.S Clothing website with an embedded database functionality to enable online recruitment.
- ▶ Build projections, budget planning, and P&L statements for the retail department.

Perry Ellis International

February 2007 - July 2019

Market Manager | New York, NY

- ▶ Opened new retail store locations across the US, including sites for Perry Ellis brand division.
- ► Assessed stores around the US to identify inefficiencies and provided Regional Managers solutions to address areas of concern and increase performance opportunities.
- ▷ Collaborated with leaders to conduct quarterly employee reviews and developed plans for employee performance and engagement.

EDUCATION

Web Development - App Academy

February 2023 - August 2023

Online

▷ TDD, scalability, algorithms, OOP, Back-end, Front-end, Full Stack, coding style, REST, security, single-page apps, pair programming, and web development best practices.

Ai Miami International University of Art & Design

October 2011 - June 2014

Miami, FL

▶ Bachelor of arts degree in fashion merchandising.

Miami Dade College

August 2008 - May 2010

Miami, FL

Graphic Design, Art, and GE courses.